<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>slitherin python</title>
      <link>/blog/slitherin-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/slitherin-python/</guid>
      <description>While in SDS 348, one of the first things we learned in Python was that Python is very flexible with string operations. The string operations allow for funny reconfiguring of letters in words, which can be see below:
first = &amp;quot;leo&amp;quot; last = &amp;quot;bobi&amp;quot; first + last ## &amp;#39;leobobi&amp;#39; last[:3]+first[2:]+&amp;#39; &amp;#39;+first[:3]+last[2:] ## &amp;#39;bobo leobi&amp;#39; 2*first[0:1] + 2*last[-1:] ## &amp;#39;llii&amp;#39; 2*(first[0:3]+last[-3:]) ## &amp;#39;leoobileoobi&amp;#39; We also learned that the strings created in Python are immutable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Heather Seiders hms2364
0. Introduction The datasets, regseasonstats and postseasonstats1 are both National Basketball Association player game statistics during the 2018-2019 basketball season. Players included in each of the datasets played 70% or more of their teams games and played at least 5 playoff games. The regseasonstats2 data observes the top 51 players from the regular season that made playoff appearances ranked by ESPN, and the postseasonstats2 data observes those that met the same 70% or more of all games played and also participated in at least 5 postseason games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Heather Seiders hms2364
Modeling Instructions A knitted R Markdown document (as a PDF) and the raw R Markdown file (as .Rmd) should both be submitted to Canvas by 11:59pm on 5/1/2020. These two documents will be graded jointly, so they must be consistent (i.e., don’t change the R Markdown file without also updating the knitted document). Knit an html copy too, for later! In the .Rmd file for Project 2, you can copy the first code-chunk into your project .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>